NIYATI: That's good.
NIYATI: Bye.
Bodha Talks: Yamuna Tidah.
Bodha Talks: Hare Krishna! Hare Krishna! Krishna Krishna!
Bodha Talks: Krishna.
Bodha Talks: But it's not the greatest smile.
Bodha Talks: Hare Krishna!
Bodha Talks: Vrishna Krishna.
Bodha Talks: This time, it's not going to be.
Bodha Talks: Haare Krishna.
Bodha Talks: Krishna Krishna already.
Bodha Talks: That's from 89.
Bodha Talks: She is a voice of the Lord. Hare Krishna, Hare Krishna, Krishna, Krishna! Hare.
Bodha Talks: Thanks.
Bodha Talks: So last week, Dharma Prayabhavu had spoken about Parikshit Maharaj.
Bodha Talks: And today we are discussing about his great-grandmother.
Bodha Talks: Put them on top.
Bodha Talks: the characters of the Bahavara, they do not only represent history, They also represent human psychology.
Bodha Talks: Therefore, the word ETHAS You know, ETS is not about what happened in the past.
Bodha Talks: It Yash also means what you will feel in the present based upon the past.
Bodha Talks: these personalities… Evoke the same eternal feeling.
Bodha Talks: Which exists in human interaction.
Bodha Talks: Therefore, Kunti, the mother of the Pandavas, in the Muhammad, Vascular explains.
Bodha Talks: The purpose of the Mahabharat is to bring out certain qualities.
Bodha Talks: in the Natasha Shastras, Yes, certainly there are heroes in the modern stories.
Bodha Talks: especially as far as I understand the Indian movies.
Bodha Talks: We focus on the heroes rather than the qualities.
Bodha Talks: And when you see from the perspective of modern dramas, the characters of the Mahabhara.
Bodha Talks: you'll be a little shocked, because in the Mahabharab, even the greatest of the heroes have vulnerable qualities.
Bodha Talks: Right?
Bodha Talks: So our question itself is redundant, because human values Human qualities are… Combination of potential and limitations.
Bodha Talks: Alrighty.
Bodha Talks: Our concept of heroes They should be free from folly.
Bodha Talks: And therefore, we become part of the Cockre Janta Party.
Bodha Talks: Right.
Bodha Talks: Okay, unless there is a freedom from all the flaws, you have no right to lead.
Bodha Talks: We will choose Duryodans.
Bodha Talks: Instead of you, they should go alive.
Bodha Talks: Even origin, for that matter, And Arjunar…
Bodha Talks: became threatened by seeing the greatness of a color of your skin. Now, we asked them.
Bodha Talks: He's not partial in expressing this. He doesn't hide this. Oh, since Arjun is my side, I cannot this part of the story.
Bodha Talks: It is there publicly visible.
Bodha Talks: You can read it. Nothing to hide.
Bodha Talks: But that quality of Arjuna being threatened by A. Columbia is not his perpetual quality.
Bodha Talks: Through the organization?
Bodha Talks: Was a junior threatened by influenza, or was Bodha threatened by…
Bodha Talks: Now, Arjuna was threatened by Eclivia. He comes in and tells that.
Bodha Talks: Okay, there's net in the Muhammad.
Bodha Talks: Right?
Bodha Talks: So when you see those limitations.
Bodha Talks: One should not be shocked and surprised, because that is how human existence is.
Bodha Talks: Whether it is Kali Yuga or Satta Yuga.
Bodha Talks: And therefore, Kunti makes so much of sense.
Bodha Talks: Right, her personality… Actually, the Mahabhara, yes, Krishna is God.
Bodha Talks: But the heroes of Mahavara are Kunti and Rhani.
Bodha Talks: Oh.
Bodha Talks: Rest everybody's side character, in one sense.
Bodha Talks: So, mother punti… sensitivity. She was so sensitive in regards to her bodily features also.
Bodha Talks: You know, all the time, her body had to be covered with Chaudhur.
Bodha Talks: Even when Karana came to… when Kunti comes to meet Karana.
Bodha Talks: Mother Tokina, he also knew that she's a mother.
Bodha Talks: Not that continual to him.
Bodha Talks: And Kunti, of course, knows that Karana is my son, so when Karana meets Kunti, Karna was offering…
Bodha Talks: published into Surreya.
Bodha Talks: After offering the oblation to Surya.
Bodha Talks: He puts a cover… he takes a cloth and covers over her hair, so that she should not feel the heat.
Bodha Talks: At the same time, imagine that was her sensitive body.
Bodha Talks: Her features were like that of the…
Bodha Talks: But at the same time, Kuntya's very tough internally.
Bodha Talks: Not only internally, imagine she traveled with the Panda Worlds, In the forest, Threatened by the gurus.
Bodha Talks: On the run to, you know, to save themselves.
Bodha Talks: They were about to be burned in the Lakshakra.
Bodha Talks: Right. So, Bhava, at points, he has to carry her on the back.
Bodha Talks: In fact, Mahabhara goes into great details.
Bodha Talks: Now, when you are going into the forest, you don't have a running water.
Bodha Talks: you don't have servants, because they… the panda was at 60,000 students when they were in exile, but here, they had to basically run away from the Lakshak Rhaba.
Bodha Talks: 5 Pandavas and Kuntri.
Bodha Talks: So, how will you fetch water for her? Because she could not go to the valley, get into, you know, whichever river, like, if you go to Bhadrina, or you go to Jimales, if you go to Rishikesh also.
Bodha Talks: You have to go to the downstream to collect the water.
Bodha Talks: So, Mahabhara gets into such a great detail.
Bodha Talks: That Dhhima, which is Uttariya, the extra cloth.
Bodha Talks: He would go into the water.
Bodha Talks: Dip his clothes in the water, and bring it up and squeeze in our mouth.
Bodha Talks: That is the process of drinking water.
Bodha Talks: To… Joe?
Bodha Talks: Radha Radhanyo convenience now.
Bodha Talks: That was not existing, but the psychology of flexibility was so great.
Bodha Talks: Jittanar kunti Murdo.
Bodha Talks: As much as she was soft, she was also very tough. That is an integration of her quality, as explained in the Bhavna.
Bodha Talks: She's very stoic, also.
Bodha Talks: In the Bhavod Gita, where Krishna explains, You know, Sharanagati, surrender.
Bodha Talks: Sometime what happens, surrender is seen as being…
Bodha Talks: Pampered by the person who's giving you protection.
Bodha Talks: I fully depend.
Bodha Talks: Now, that fully dependence on whether our superiors, parents, teachers, God.
Bodha Talks: You know, being carefree. Now, Sharanagat is not about being carefree in regards to our day-to-day activities.
Bodha Talks: Carefree is the mindset. It is not the physical reality. Physical reality is being very alert.
Bodha Talks: Satta Kapa.
Bodha Talks: No? So therefore, when Sharadhargati is presented, unfortunately, when, we talk about Sharna Ratihi.
Bodha Talks: Our Sharanagati has become the Sharanagati of being carefree, of not taking any responsibility.
Bodha Talks: No, imagine dealing with that contradiction, that you're completely alert on a physical platform, your Bodhti, your mind, your ego, your Indriyas are alert.
Bodha Talks: But your consciousness is gainful.
Bodha Talks: That is what yoga is.
Bodha Talks: They're not.
Bodha Talks: The World Cup happened now, right? FIFA World Cup.
Bodha Talks: one football player, And I heard something.
Bodha Talks: When he was playing, there was a match about to come.
Bodha Talks: And he was in anxiety. Father said, what is this? You're playing and you're in anxiety, kilna anxiety ko, durka. You play to be freed from anxiety.
Bodha Talks: He said, if you want to be in anxiety, I will take you to some place. So the father drove his son
Bodha Talks: to ghettos.
Bodha Talks: Where people were struggling to get their next meal. He said, this is the place to be anxiety. He said, here, whether you win or lose, you still make money. What is the point of being anxiety?
Bodha Talks: Is it the purpose of place to select a lot. You work very hard.
Bodha Talks: There is no other place where people work hard than sports, whether it is basketball, tennis, football, except cricket.
Bodha Talks: Nope.
Bodha Talks: Cricketmate, look, come, hard work.
Bodha Talks: And especially if you are playing a test match.
Bodha Talks: So you are sweating so much, at the same time you are supposed to be carefree, and therefore sports symbolizes life itself.
Bodha Talks: All right.
Bodha Talks: So… Kunti, what does she do?
Bodha Talks: She struggles very hard.
Bodha Talks: And when she struggles very hard.
Bodha Talks: her struggling, there is no pampering of herself. In fact, some philosopher said, life is a constant war.
Bodha Talks: Jeeva aur dummy koi Antharne, externally.
Bodha Talks: They paid me even a tree to survive, even though it is called a starboard.
Bodha Talks: It is immovable, but regularly even the tree moves.
Bodha Talks: Right? The trees fell off.
Bodha Talks: Many trees were moving. Only those trees were very strong. They were shaking, mowing, but they were not uprooted. That means they were very healthy.
Bodha Talks: Stagulancy for whatever reason.
Bodha Talks: Because there is a comfort, there is a lot of facility, I don't have to worry about my future.
Bodha Talks: That is different from Spratta.
Bodha Talks: Stability and stagnancy are two different things. Stability… is what? Stability is internal.
Bodha Talks: calculating.
Bodha Talks: And therefore, puntil… It represents that very, very nicely, and therefore, Mahabharat explains.
Bodha Talks: What does Kunte represent? Which quality does she represent?
Bodha Talks: Kunti represents the quality of determination, Tradhartha.
Bodha Talks: Right. Pushkander AIC grita aai.
Bodha Talks: And therefore, that gritta is not born out of simple, superficial affirmations. That's called Chaudhana, right? You know, you should have an affirmation, everything will be alright.
Bodha Talks: This is the one philosopher said.
Bodha Talks: That pessimism is the sign of decaying.
Bodha Talks: Optimism is the sign of superficiality. So profound, so real.
Bodha Talks: Tragic optimism is the mood of the strong person, who seeks intensity and fullness of life.
Bodha Talks: And therefore, strife is the law of life.
Bodha Talks: Right?
Bodha Talks: This is the law of life. You cannot… nobody changes, even God does not change this. Rather, He prepares you.
Bodha Talks: There is a famous philosopher, You know, in the Western world, Spinoza, Very interesting.
Bodha Talks: He said, when you study properly the Western religion, He was born Jewish.
Bodha Talks: But he saw God is more of a fascinating
Bodha Talks: You know, like a hero comes… to rescue.
Bodha Talks: At least in the books.
Bodha Talks: But he said, what I learned by studying nature, he was ostracized.
Bodha Talks: He was ostracized by the Jewish community. Eventually, when Christians were angry, liberal country, you know, owing against any of their values, you are officially ostracized.
Bodha Talks: And part of ostracizing is a prayer curse.
Bodha Talks: You know, get the rent, The rights that comes.
Bodha Talks: Every aspect of your life should be cursed. They are condemning officially
Bodha Talks: You know, through a proper system.
Bodha Talks: But he did not mind, he said, I'm looking for connection with the real world.
Bodha Talks: To Islio Kakada, what he says, determination, explaining very dutifully.
Bodha Talks: He said, why should we accept the philosophy of determinism?
Bodha Talks: There is a free will, and there is a deterministic idea. We can say in our
Bodha Talks: You know, not exactly, but we can translate karma and freebill.
Bodha Talks: Diver or freely?
Bodha Talks: Now, very interesting.
Bodha Talks: When you accept the philosophy of determinism, it is not that you're accepting Arika regard, this is what our life is.
Bodha Talks: He said, this theory of determinism is again a psychological mindset.
Bodha Talks: In regards to war, you're still endeavoring.
Bodha Talks: You do everything to change, but your mindset should be, this has come to me as part of my life, I will accept it.
Bodha Talks: Lord Brahma, who's the creator of the universe, he, in his prayers.
Bodha Talks: He explains to… he's offering prayers to Krishna, Taktinu Kampa. He said, whatever comes to me as a quota.
Bodha Talks: Good or bad. BOJAM, I will accept with graceful heart.
Bodha Talks: Yeah, mindset, and again, try to understand, this is the mindset.
Bodha Talks: This is not your action. A mindset called Laker, keeping this mindset in your heart, you do everything what is required to move forward in this world. And that's what Kunti represents so beautifully.
Bodha Talks: Right?
Bodha Talks: So, therefore, what is… what is tragic optimism? Tragic optimism is, you know this is the reality, but still, I will work hard to make something positive.
Bodha Talks: And what was the tragic in Kuddhist life?
Bodha Talks: No. Kunti lost her husband.
Bodha Talks: Before losing a husband, husband lost his position as the king of the hostilenapur.
Bodha Talks: Sort of suddenly he was cursed.
Bodha Talks: You know, if he… if he comes in contact with his wife, he'll be killed.
Bodha Talks: So, Panda Maharaj abruptly gave up Hustinnapur, and he came to the forest.
Bodha Talks: And then… you know, he died according to the curse, and Gunti was alone with her five sons.
Bodha Talks: Madhrid said, it is easier to die than to live.
Bodha Talks: You know, we only see her as Sattva glorified here.
Bodha Talks: Sattiko glorify kiawa.
Bodha Talks: Living is much greater than dying for a higher cause. Therefore, Madhari says, you know what, I cannot handle this.
Bodha Talks: One is I cannot handle the challenges of life. Second, it is impossible and difficult for me to breathe.
Bodha Talks: Not partial to my children.
Bodha Talks: To be equal to all the fines 5 license will be difficult, therefore work?
Bodha Talks: You can handle this aap jit raw meini me Chaudhuri.
Bodha Talks: Right.
Bodha Talks: So, Madhre is not glorified so much as much as Punta is glorified.
Bodha Talks: hi.
Bodha Talks: Rajput on kasuti hoge, because it was as good as Punti Hogi.
Bodha Talks: And then when she was raising her children, they were comfortable in the forest.
Bodha Talks: It was not, like, dense forest.
Bodha Talks: It was like a ashram, where all the sages, all the retired king had come there, giving up all their ambitions.
Bodha Talks: Competition kamtar.
Bodha Talks: Bhav people had chosen to be there and live with less.
Bodha Talks: You know, minimalism or Aram Shah practice coming.
Bodha Talks: I mean, you're raised in such a background.
Bodha Talks: there is a lot of peace. Recently, I was in Nasikh, and there was this gurukul, about 50 kids were there, they're studying the Vedas.
Bodha Talks: They come when they are 6 to 7 years old. Every day, 3 hours, they study Vedas.
Bodha Talks: Now, studying Vedas is not learning stories. Studying Vedas is basically learning the Veda.
Bodha Talks: O guru BOHA bush po repeat karuti.
Bodha Talks: Because there is no entertainment. You just… Hear and recite.
Bodha Talks: And for 7 years, they do like that.
Bodha Talks: Now, 3 hours VED study, then there is a Sanskrit.
Bodha Talks: Then they study of that subject.
Bodha Talks: Machas, but you look to.
Bodha Talks: Poras algo que el me mental.
Bodha Talks: Come on.
Bodha Talks: But then, nispapata, Jon nispata, na? Innocence.
Bodha Talks: In the modern world, that nishvatta is synonymous to ignorance.
Bodha Talks: Because they become irrelevant to the real world unless their Veda is made into Bhavar.
Bodha Talks: And that's what we were discussing with our main teacher, and he agreed. Yes, makes sense. Imagine Parvas were like that.
Bodha Talks: There's no concept of duality. Everything was happiness, pleasure, you know, comfort, sport, ha?
Bodha Talks: So, Punti decided to stay there.
Bodha Talks: Right.
Bodha Talks: But then… She was told, no, this is not your place.
Bodha Talks: They are not meant to be here, you have to go to Hasnapur jantar Mantra keba, jana pada y aapko.
Bodha Talks: Hello?
Bodha Talks: Imagine when she comes to Hasturnapur.
Bodha Talks: The first thing happens is that everywhere the Radharashtravenish people, they spread misinformation.
Bodha Talks: The wrong narrative is the battle which was fought from very beginning.
Bodha Talks: Wang Qing becomes a hero.
Bodha Talks: Anu is also not made after him. Imagine that itself is the biggest hijack.
Bodha Talks: But now you cannot say anything against him, because internals are an emotional outbursts there.
Bodha Talks: It takes time to rebuild a narrative. So when Kunti comes to Hastinnapur, what does she hear? That all her sons are illegitimate.
Bodha Talks: They are born illicit.
Bodha Talks: Welcome ahead.
Bodha Talks: Pando Maharaj is not their father.
Bodha Talks: And the boys are not small babies.
Bodha Talks: out of June, Lost this further, When he was 14-year-old.
Bodha Talks: On the day of Arjuna's birthday, Pandu Maharaj left this world. Arjuna's 14-year-old, Dharma's 15-year-old, Minister Mahara's 16-year-old. When you come to Austinnapur.
Bodha Talks: Imagine, what do they hear? They hear about their own birth.
Bodha Talks: Their work was questioned by the entire Not the citizen alone!
Bodha Talks: the state itself, agar aapke Rajane aapke citizenship.
Bodha Talks: People fit it and shape it.
Bodha Talks: Your… your birth itself is question, Imagine what kind of,
Bodha Talks: You know, problem they must have gone through.
Bodha Talks: But what did they learn in forest? One thing they learn in the forest is… stability.
Bodha Talks: So, Kunti did not waver. Pain, Rhaegar, there was a pain. You can't avoid the pain.
Bodha Talks: But the beauty of Kunti was, how does she handle her team?
Bodha Talks: She did not water her pain and made it much more, like Bhavav Gita Krishna explains. Samoch Sattva is not about becoming free from emotion.
Bodha Talks: Sama Chittna Thom is not becoming free from reaction.
Bodha Talks: Sama Chattathun, or equality, is minimizing the duality.
Bodha Talks: The pain will be there.
Bodha Talks: ko.
Bodha Talks: Do not make that as your contemplation.
Bodha Talks: Alright.
Bodha Talks: So that is one aspect of Kutri.
Bodha Talks: And then, when she comes to Hasturnapur, when she's hearing about this, there is an inner pain.
Bodha Talks: her conflict.
Bodha Talks: What is Kuntish conflict? Kuntish conflict is the conflict of her son's birth.
Bodha Talks: Got it all.
Bodha Talks: Ashtakhan today also more now, There are more people condemn Kunti for abandoning Karva.
Bodha Talks: Right. Without even giving an attention to what is her story.
Bodha Talks: I remember when, there was a story which, there was a lady married to a very big person.
Bodha Talks: Before marriage only, I told her, I can give you money, but no time.
Bodha Talks: You choose. You want me, you'll get all the facility, but I cannot guarantee any time.
Bodha Talks: So she agreed for this marriage.
Bodha Talks: And sure enough, she was not able to get any time, so she started going to Jimmy. This is an American school, you know?
Bodha Talks: Those where she fell in love with the gym instructor, but he put certain condition.
Bodha Talks: And then, what happened was… You know, there was raining heavily.
Bodha Talks: And she had to come back, and she had to cross a bridge.
Bodha Talks: She was not able to cross the bridge.
Bodha Talks: And she comes back, and she takes a boat.
Bodha Talks: to go across.
Bodha Talks: And when she looks for the money, she had no money because she had lost her ballot. She did not bring the ballot, it was not there in the car also. And the boatman said, you know what? He said, I can't take you unless you pay me. She said, you know, look, I am a very… you know, I come from a good family, you can see.
Bodha Talks: They said, doesn't matter. They said, madam, I need the money, unless you have the money, I will not take you instead.
Bodha Talks: She was very angry, she went to her…
Bodha Talks: boyfriend who said, look, only love, no interaction, we had already promised. He did not give her the money. It's a story.
Bodha Talks: Don't ask questions about the story. So then she took her car, she drove over the bridge, and because it was raining heavily, she drowned.
Bodha Talks: Now, story is not important, the question is important, who is at fault?
Bodha Talks: It's Cardoshi.
Bodha Talks: Alright.
Bodha Talks: a Doshi.
Bodha Talks: And if you see, everybody will find faults with everybody else.
Bodha Talks: Vendal Ka Doshi.
Bodha Talks: So you always find thought rather than actually hearing the story and empathizing with the situation.
Bodha Talks: We are judgmental.
Bodha Talks: story ko sunke chintan mei ka.
Bodha Talks: Alright.
Bodha Talks: So, kuntike Sattva Turan judgment, immediately, without even understanding what she must have gone through.
Bodha Talks: What was our situation?
Bodha Talks: kartiya.
Bodha Talks: She had that conflict in her heart continuously, all the time, because she was not able to tell anybody. The time, the timing was not there. When she revealed the store, Judith Dharma.
Bodha Talks: Eventually, she revealed her story to Yashir. After the war is over.
Bodha Talks: And they're doing Sattvdha to everyone. And she tells… you should also do Svta to kara.
Bodha Talks: He was very shocked. He said, why, Karanhan?
Bodha Talks: Because he's your older brother.
Bodha Talks: He's stunned and shocked.
Bodha Talks: Krishna had not revealed them.
Bodha Talks: Kunti had not revealed them.
Bodha Talks: Dishma knew he had not reverted.
Bodha Talks: VIDURA name, he had not revealed.
Bodha Talks: None of them there will continue to steal.
Bodha Talks: And he was so pain. Then, Vidish Maharaj makes one statement. He said, whenever I saw the feet of Karana, it reminded me of my mother.
Bodha Talks: And Rapod explains… Very interesting. He told one of the secretaries
Bodha Talks: He asked, he saw his speak, your mother must be very innocent, very grateful.
Bodha Talks: Now, how do you know?
Bodha Talks: So, when I read this in the Mahabhara, the Yashtraumara said, when I would see the feet of…
Bodha Talks: Karana, I would always remember Mother Kunti as a cue, Hello?
Bodha Talks: now I can realize that, mother, why did you do this to me?
Bodha Talks: Even Yenis Thiel, who is very…
Bodha Talks: A person who empathizes, what did you this year do? He cursed Kunti, and he cursed everybody else also.
Bodha Talks: You know, he curse like that. Whether it's curse worked or not, you don't know. It's worked.
Bodha Talks: Then she comes to Yashdim.
Bodha Talks: She comes to Yashade, alright, because she did not get any solace from her son, rather she got a curse.
Bodha Talks: No? And then she comes to Yudhistil, the ass of the room.
Bodha Talks: And she tells her story to us.
Bodha Talks: She tells her entire new or so.
Bodha Talks: The beauty of Vashdale, You know, rather than empathizing with her.
Bodha Talks: Rather than sympathizing with her, rather than chastising with her, he used another, totally different perspective to Kuntri.
Bodha Talks: very interesting perspective. He says, my dear Kuti, you know what?
Bodha Talks: He said, the powerful have the power to digest anything water comes into their life.
Bodha Talks: Ja.
Bodha Talks: Of course, he explains karma factor, everything, but he concludes with this. He said, you should not take it seriously because your powerful personality
Bodha Talks: Mental strength, physical strength ko Bodha se hail.
Bodha Talks: Like, pretty early in the morning, one devotee.
Bodha Talks: You know, father is extremely sick.
Bodha Talks: And not on the… when a man is Sigma.
Bodha Talks: It is very difficult to handle them, because they still have their ego of being very self-independent, you know, very difficult.
Bodha Talks: He's a hard-working person, So… and these are both the sisters, or… no sons, only daughters, are they?
Bodha Talks: And one daughter is not in India, so the daughter is taking care of her father.
Bodha Talks: Caring is not a problem, because she loves her father.
Bodha Talks: But in the process of caring, there is exhaustion.
Bodha Talks: Takano.
Bodha Talks: Alright, tell you that.
Bodha Talks: resources, hey, if you have resources, I say, I told him, he said, you hire people, physical care a month, karong.
Bodha Talks: Emotional care akaro, if you try to do physical, then emotional also won't be able to provide.
Bodha Talks: You know, so Kunti, what Yashude Dev told you, said, you're powerful, no karma for you. There is no reaction for you.
Bodha Talks: Very important, when you become very powerful and strong, you have the power to digest
Bodha Talks: Agara, sick ho, weak ho, you lack resources, your life is perpetually feeling guilty, perpetually feeling low, perpetually feeling that my karma is very bad.
Bodha Talks: And therefore, Mother Kunti, She heard that. It's like, it's like having a passport.
Bodha Talks: If you have an American passport, kita na bhi America BODHU.
Bodha Talks: Ap kita nabi UK kugwanito.
Bodha Talks: Why? Not only Indians, even the Pakistanis. Pakistan is hate America.
Bodha Talks: But everybody wants to go down there.
Bodha Talks: Musk educational institution, even the… some of the relatives of Indian sannyasis.
Bodha Talks: They will send their children to study their own. E reality.
Bodha Talks: Right? American passport, you can go to anywhere. Indian passport, not right.
Bodha Talks: So, what do we learn from this story? That Satta hai.
Bodha Talks: kai.
Bodha Talks: He's able to give that.
Bodha Talks: So, I like that idea of Anthii getting this information from Yash Sadeva. Up until then.
Bodha Talks: She had all the feeling of guilt, continuously.
Bodha Talks: Right? So, she handled this ethical conflict.
Bodha Talks: Again, Kunti, asking Drakody, Now, again, it's a very controversial story.
Bodha Talks: Everyday Panda was whatever they would collect.
Bodha Talks: big Shah, because they were acting as a Brahmana, they would come and offer it to Mother Pulti. And what Pulte would do, she would divide it into two parts.
Bodha Talks: Egg Bhavata.
Bodha Talks: Aur baki ka Bhavir sehne Bhag mein, Devi karke bakunogate.
Bodha Talks: Because…
Bodha Talks: One can say, how this is… how can… how can we do like that? Because socialism is not a reality.
Bodha Talks: kaniki?
Bodha Talks: i.
Bodha Talks: So, nobody objected. The Pandavas did not object to Dharma eating more than anyone of them.
Bodha Talks: So, when they come.
Bodha Talks: They say, mother, we have brought the Dhik Shah. And what could they say? Bodkar ka.
Bodha Talks: We'll distribute amongst all of you.
Bodha Talks: Then Radhan and Yashtu said, what is this? He said, mother, this is not Bhik Shah, this is Sri Rahman.
Bodha Talks: Now, in Bhav, there is an interesting concept.
Bodha Talks: nigga.
Bodha Talks: Or at the same time, jo mere Mus. You cannot share her with anybody and everybody.
Bodha Talks: Many people are like, usko would rather, you know, let her married to Rattoon.
Bodha Talks: but… So, Kunti here says, how do you reconcile between what I said?
Bodha Talks: And what we are supposed to do.
Bodha Talks: Radharhani hunachi.
Bodha Talks: It's unheardable.
Bodha Talks: So then Radhimaraj told Arjuna, he said, you should marry her. Since… You won her.
Bodha Talks: Paradhanimalayani hula.
Bodha Talks: Mene jitar, lekin body… Manchella icon.
Bodha Talks: Then Yidhar Maharaj, and all the Pandavas, it explained that everybody looked at Dharapadi with longing. Then Yiddisha Maharaj made a statement.
Bodha Talks: He said, mother, We will all marry her together.
Bodha Talks: And Yiddish Tumaraj makes one statement. He said.
Bodha Talks: It has come in my mind, it has to be Dharma.
Bodha Talks: We cannot, right? So one may say, if you need only that part, you'll say, Yashtra Mahara is a narcissistic, arrogant. Kunti is so arrogant. She's so focused on making her world come true.
Bodha Talks: Even though she knows this is not correct Dharma.
Bodha Talks: But why did they make that statement just few days before Vazdar had come to them and told the entire story?
Bodha Talks: I'll dropper this background.
Bodha Talks: Hinder the other.
Bodha Talks: It was not predicted, it is not that it's going to happen like this only. He had given a hint.
Bodha Talks: And when this came from our mouth, it was not coming from her alone, it was divine arrangement. It doesn't stop here. We have to prove it's a divine arrangement.
Bodha Talks: Darshtha Bhimna comes there.
Bodha Talks: to look who is this… who are these people who have come to get about done. Sister, when he gets to know about this, he comes to his father.
Bodha Talks: Ya dabiendo que acorno.
Bodha Talks: You know, all of them, they're going to marry our sister.
Bodha Talks: Then, the father, Drupad Maharaj, comes and said, hey, what is this?
Bodha Talks: This is not there in the scripture. It is not there in the tradition, Nok Pramar or Shastr Pramar. Don't know meaning here. How can you allow this to happen?
Bodha Talks: Then Masner comes again.
Bodha Talks: Krishna also comes there.
Bodha Talks: Did they tell the entire story of Rhupadi to the Pandavas. They asked him, he says, this is going to happen, you cannot stop it.
Bodha Talks: But itna holy kebar, even after having all this story, really, When Dhraupadi was being disrupted, they're tempted.
Bodha Talks: What is the story? Because you can't… why? You can't tell everybody Scripture.
Bodha Talks: You can't tell this far-out story. What is the story of Dharupada to the ordinary people?
Bodha Talks: Karana, in fact, says, how can somebody has 5 husbands, having 5 husbands, mentions a prostitute, mentions a prostitute, making her Venkh, doesn't matter.
Bodha Talks: Imagine what Kunte had to go through
Bodha Talks: And it was ordered, upper seh ordered ahila, aap kitna bhi Bhavnakaro, kusko Badalna asam Bhavna, and the destiny and the history will not stand by you.
Bodha Talks: History will always stand against you.
Bodha Talks: Kunti and Dropodi had to experience that the entire history would go against them, and all the literatures, all the writing, however much you talk about it, people will come back and speak ill about them.
Bodha Talks: And sending Dharma for confrontation.
Bodha Talks: you know, against Bakasur.
Bodha Talks: Because she knew that every day, regularly, not every day, whoever goes to kill that Bodha sur, they get killed.
Bodha Talks: And she chooses her son to go.
Bodha Talks: to Bakashur. And Yidhishtu Maharaj objects very strongly. How can we do this to him, my dear mother?
Bodha Talks: Here we see the confidence of Kunti.
Bodha Talks: kaya.
Bodha Talks: And I've seen what they're going through.
Bodha Talks: And therefore, whether my son… Able to do the job or not.
Bodha Talks: It doesn't matter, we have to reciprocate.
Bodha Talks: Like a great mother of a warrior.
Bodha Talks: Other day, I was in Doshi Kisha, and I was a former doctor and director. He's a child specialist.
Bodha Talks: And he was telling me a story of one of these patients who'd come to him regularly.
Bodha Talks: Eventually, he became a lieutenant colonel in the Indian Army.
Bodha Talks: And he was skilled while fighting the terrorists.
Bodha Talks: It was for Mehdaro, Bhna Sunava, Dr. Rhanke Radharakam.
Bodha Talks: He was killed.
Bodha Talks: And you would come to me, even after being an army officer, I came to you.
Bodha Talks: And when he lost his life, he had a wife and a small daughter.
Bodha Talks: Very powerful for the family.
Bodha Talks: But this girl joined the army. No, the wife joined the army.
Bodha Talks: Except, I want to join. So, it is spirit hana kuntika.
Bodha Talks: And therefore, Kunti explains the motherhood to a traditional Maharaj through Krishna.
Bodha Talks: You know, the spirit of valor and warrior, along with that caring, was so beautifully there in Punti. She tells Yiddish Primha very profound about mother.
Bodha Talks: When she tells you, Dister, they say, don't be reluctant, leader.
Bodha Talks: You have to fight this war, my dear son. You have to fight this war for Dharma.
Bodha Talks: You have a Brahminical tendency, but you have to encourage your Akshatriya tendency. She tells this to Krishna, we tell this to Yodhis students, she says about… talks about four stages of motherhood.
Bodha Talks: She said the first stage of motherhood is…
Bodha Talks: Carrying the baby into Dhartri, Dharan karne walko, Dhartri kahw.
Bodha Talks: Even to hold the baby in the womb takes a lot of courage.
Bodha Talks: And a lot of good karma.
Bodha Talks: Nowadays we know how much there is infertility.
Bodha Talks: That is the first thing, Rharanharna.
Bodha Talks: Jalani.
Bodha Talks: That is the second stage, my dear Krishna.
Bodha Talks: Daftri, 2nd Jamani, And third, my dear Yudishhil.
Bodha Talks: Actually, mother Bhana. Nourish karna usko.
Bodha Talks: Feeding the milk, Then, feeding knowledge. Shastr ketaki, Prattama Guru, mother is the first guru of the child.
Bodha Talks: Although, Ivat Upanishad is speaking about this, not only the Quranas.
Bodha Talks: Not only the tradition, not only the culture.
Bodha Talks: And the fourth, Daftri, Janani, Ambar, and fourth is called as Veerasi. Veerasyaniki, Veer Puttronko, Janu Dhinavani.
Bodha Talks: And therefore, sheltered confidence, letting go.
Bodha Talks: At the same time, along with the confidence, the pay is there, I might lose him.
Bodha Talks: No warrior's mother sending her son or daughter around is also. No, they are not that kind of blunt confidence. Along with that confidence, there is still that caring of mother, and that's what makes them completely surrender.
Bodha Talks: to God.
Bodha Talks: Right?
Bodha Talks: So therefore, the path which Kunti chose Was not necessarily convenient.
Bodha Talks: But it was just…
Bodha Talks: So, therefore, What do we learn from Punti's life?
Bodha Talks: We learn from Gunti's life-based combination of… Shah Alam Rati.
Bodha Talks: And full human endeavor.
Bodha Talks: And therefore, when you study her life, she was a philosopher.
Bodha Talks: She was a queen. She was a lady.
Bodha Talks: She was a devotee.
Bodha Talks: Her life, what she prepared in Hastinnapur, And our affection for Krishna.
Bodha Talks: Like, we read in the Bhavar, prayers are there, where she's offering prayers to Krishna.
Bodha Talks: that, my dear Lord, And remove all my attachment.
Bodha Talks: One of the most amazing prayer.
Bodha Talks: What does she say to Krishna? My dear Krishna.
Bodha Talks: He said, remove my attachment from my father's side.
Bodha Talks: And remove my attachment from my husband's side.
Bodha Talks: Let my heart flow.
Bodha Talks: Non-stop at your local suite.
Bodha Talks: E preunderen.
Bodha Talks: But to offer this prayer, one has to be affectionate.
Bodha Talks: You know, just to say Radh mujik oyanse lena denan krod ye karan BOA.
Bodha Talks: Neglect ke current sakte ho. Irresponsibility ke current sakteho.
Bodha Talks: You know, trying to be attached to God.
Bodha Talks: Sometime it is a very good way to…
Bodha Talks: deny one's a responsibility. I think somebody was telling me.
Bodha Talks: Nowadays, we see many people go to Primal Marath, Virat Kohli, you know, Saphlo Gathan, Bhavanke pass.
Bodha Talks: Actually, one story happened many nights.
Bodha Talks: You know, one girl… She was inconvenienced in the marriage.
Bodha Talks: And she came in touch with the Bhav Sharma that the Bhakti…
Bodha Talks: Push team, or Gaudihar, whatever, you know?
Bodha Talks: So she chose to break her marriage, file the complaint against her husband.
Bodha Talks: She got a very good, alumini.
Bodha Talks: Now she's shunting God's name, staying in Bhindav.
Bodha Talks: Now, this is not what Kunte is asking about cutting off her attachment.
Bodha Talks: And when she's offering this prayer, she's offering this prayer.
Bodha Talks: Not to cut the affection. Sharanagati does not denote cutting the affection. Sharanagati denotes not having obsession in regards to what I choose to be done by my children.
Bodha Talks: Or anybody, for that matter.
Bodha Talks: Isi lek ke walis pra kunako Badna ki saareh mere attachment ko di kal ach kal logo mein samadhani.
Bodha Talks: You know, more than affection, there is hatred.
Bodha Talks: You know, more than, you know, sensitivity, there is indifference.
Bodha Talks: Right? And therefore.
Bodha Talks: We see, when people talk about surrendering to God, there is more about hatred of the relationship
Bodha Talks: then healthy surrender to God.
Bodha Talks: Kunti doesn't fall into that category.
Bodha Talks: When we read her prayer, We need to read a life also.
Bodha Talks: She never gave up her affection to the Padnabas.
Bodha Talks: She is giving these words to Krishna, he has to fight this war. The best mother, the ordinary mother, would say Rakuten.
Bodha Talks: No, there is no need for you to fight. Kunti should have told that to Yudishhil Maharaj, and he had that character, reluctancy to fight. Yudhishtu Maharaj was happy to fight Yashi. But Kulti gives that inspiration to Yashtraum Maharaj. At the same time, she's able to say, Krishna.
Bodha Talks: Take away the attachment.
Bodha Talks: nihari.
Bodha Talks: Same thing with Rapidioles.
Bodha Talks: When Rapadi was being disrobed.
Bodha Talks: It is not that her Sharanagati to Krishna was synonymous to cutting a relationship with her husband.
Bodha Talks: Anshin fracture, all the reason.
Bodha Talks: Whatever the partner was, did they deserve to be?
Bodha Talks: Renounced. They deserve to be denounced. They deserve to be punished.
Bodha Talks: In fact, one great poet says.
Bodha Talks: The Parandavas needed to be punished, like Bhishma, Dhrona, Krupa, Borisva, and all the Chauras, because they did not take any action against the culprits.
Bodha Talks: Pap karneva?
Bodha Talks: Annyai karnevala, or Annai ko dekaniwala, or Annai ko deki Detectives karnevala Bodha kribani.
Bodha Talks: When he philosophized the criminal, what was the philosophy of the Bhavas since we have been, you know, slaves?
Bodha Talks: We ought to follow the Dharma of this name.
Bodha Talks: But what was their Dharma? Whether you're a slave or not, if someone is in difficulty, you have to transcend all this limitation and fight and die. They became less than the Venture Jedi.
Bodha Talks: Little.
Bodha Talks: To kisune Bajaya.
Bodha Talks: Drop it in the chat.
Bodha Talks: Krishna saw that Mangal lay in the neck of drapadi iski kara nuka Bhika. So they also deserve the same death penalty. It was…
Bodha Talks: you know, such a crime. And what did Rharapadi do? Dharapadi did not renounce the husband.
Bodha Talks: Right, she was able to reconcile between her relationship.
Bodha Talks: And a complete shelter of Krishna, and that's what Kunti and Dropodi represent this very, very nicely.
Bodha Talks: Right? And the last one… the… I touched it upon, human endeavor, Got him up!
Bodha Talks: You know, Karma has… They're alone.
Bodha Talks: Yes.
Bodha Talks: Understanding karma. Karma has two components. One is acceptance, and second is human endeavor.
Bodha Talks: Generally, we think karma to the acceptance alone.
Bodha Talks: But karma is not only acceptance, karma is also human endeavor.
Bodha Talks: Where do you accept?
Bodha Talks: Accept what cannot be changed, Build inner resonance, develop spiritual maturity. It's an inner quality.
Bodha Talks: This is the deterministic theory practiced in your heart.
Bodha Talks: And what is human endeavor change? What can be changed? Pandavas were in the forest made them the king.
Bodha Talks: Build external strength.
Bodha Talks: She gave advice to the funders to become VIDRC.
Bodha Talks: Helplessnessing. Virgo.
Bodha Talks: Fulfill one's responsibility.
Bodha Talks: Alright, Kunti fulfilled her responsibility, stayed with them.
Bodha Talks: And when the Pandavas got married to Rhrapaji, the greatest responsibility what Kunti did.
Bodha Talks: You know, recently, one devotee got married, and I was speaking to Radharanhanipharaj.
Bodha Talks: And some other this story came.
Bodha Talks: And he said, this is so significant.
Bodha Talks: A mother who invests raising her children.
Bodha Talks: Unfortunately, she becomes unconsciously responsible in causing conflict in her relationship with her own daughter-in-law.
Bodha Talks: it becomes extremely difficult to empower the son and the daughter-in-law.
Bodha Talks: I'm gonna time there that Talks button.
Bodha Talks: She stayed in Hospinnapur, You know, facing the…
Bodha Talks: You know, the original cockroach Sattvaidi of Duryadhan Doshan Shaquddin, VIDURQ, osqui Par environment.
Bodha Talks: And then she allowed… Property to handle all our sons.
Bodha Talks: Right.
Bodha Talks: Therefore, what we learned from this.
Bodha Talks: There is no conflict in regards to our past and our endeavor. Karama…
Bodha Talks: Or prayers may conflict may be.
Bodha Talks: Jisko acceptance karna usko accept karna hain. Us keysad 11am yan.
Bodha Talks: Oh, internal reality, yeah, that's an internal reality.
Bodha Talks: And this cheese ko Bhavnakilah, but I asked her, nauseko Bhavna. This is one of the questions people ask, if somebody… recently, somebody asked this question, I'll calculate this.
Bodha Talks: that if I'm serving cows, ho.
Bodha Talks: Then I get to know that this… one of the animals is suffering so bad.
Bodha Talks: Do I have the right to…
Bodha Talks: You know, give them an injection, and take away their bite.
Bodha Talks: De Braslaya.
Bodha Talks: So there was another person we were doing hardware for.
Bodha Talks: Yeah, I'll be involved with something else.
Bodha Talks: So there was another devotee, she knew the philosophy, they said, this is not interference.
Bodha Talks: What are we doing? Here, we are interfering into somebody else's karma.
Bodha Talks: Trying to minimize their suffering quota.
Bodha Talks: And in the name of mercy, we are taking away their life.
Bodha Talks: Always at the right.
Bodha Talks: Then I said, look, technically, what you're saying is right, but karma is not only based on technical reality.
Bodha Talks: Karma is also based upon intention to reality.
Bodha Talks: If somebody is serving the animals, serving people so nicely.
Bodha Talks: And if they choose, oh, there is so much of suffering, and take away their life.
Bodha Talks: Will the Lord of the Karma
Bodha Talks: will punish them. I said, I will not answer this question.
Bodha Talks: Because, you know, according to Krishna, it says.
Bodha Talks: in the Bhavav Gita, karma Bhatti is very calm, very deep.
Bodha Talks: Kim Karmaiti, Kim Akaramehi.
Bodha Talks: I said, even the Kavais, the great poets also disturb.
Bodha Talks: I said, now, this is not to be answered.
Bodha Talks: This is to be reflected.
Bodha Talks: There are certain laws which are unchangeable. You put your hand in the fire, it does not matter why you put your hand in the fire. Whether you're putting your hand in the fire to save some baby, it will burn. Because that is the law of those elevators.
Bodha Talks: If you don't know how to swim, if you try to save somebody, you'll drown. It doesn't matter whether you're trying to save or not. If you don't know swim, you'll drown. That is the law.
Bodha Talks: Bak karti intention konne dekti.
Bodha Talks: You know, she's blind in regards to law.
Bodha Talks: If you stay a whole night.
Bodha Talks: Shadowing somebody, or you stay a full night watching
Bodha Talks: some drama, the body will react to that. There is no distinction between the act and the purpose.
Bodha Talks: Please understand.
Bodha Talks: Sapkh.
Bodha Talks: These are unchangeable.
Bodha Talks: But when it comes to a certain event based upon intention, Dasi car.
Bodha Talks: Alright, who am I to give that answer? That is Bhavil his core, her core.
Bodha Talks: I choose to deliver them.
Bodha Talks: And what she's doing, she's carrying so many animals.
Bodha Talks: He said, answer is not easy.
Bodha Talks: Therefore, even in the… there are a lot of… there are books written on this, justice?
Bodha Talks: and ethics.
Bodha Talks: You know, justice is one sense very easy.
Bodha Talks: It's a black and white.
Bodha Talks: But ethic is very subtle. Ethical is very subtle, because that is between you and Bhavana.
Bodha Talks: and Gunti, You know, you see her life.
Bodha Talks: You know, dealing with this so subtly, so sensitive.
Bodha Talks: ayadhan.
Bodha Talks: Right?
Bodha Talks: Even if you feel, okay, there are certain faults, the Bhavatam explains what does when you take shelter of God with all this background.
Bodha Talks: When your Sharanalati is connected with all this background, then your Sharonaliti becomes very profound. It is not superficial. It is not ritualistic.
Bodha Talks: It is not simply an act like a ritual.
Bodha Talks: It is very performant.
Bodha Talks: karte sarahan.
Bodha Talks: Even though my intention was not to make any mistake, the mistake must have happened, and therefore, Krishna, I accept the consequences of this.
Bodha Talks: You know, under your guidance, you choose whatever you want to give me. And therefore, this Chaudh.
Bodha Talks: He told a lie.
Bodha Talks: Judith is the son of Kunti. Chaudhar.
Bodha Talks: Krishna suggest kyata, Krishna order me kyata. Krishna did not order me this year to lie, so that Rhhanachara can be killed.
Bodha Talks: He gave the suggestion, because ultimately.
Bodha Talks: The consequences lies with the person who makes the decision.
Bodha Talks: So, Yashir took that decision.
Bodha Talks: And after the war was over, because he lied to his guru.
Bodha Talks: Vidhistra Maharaj did seek help for some moment.
Bodha Talks: For either action ko, consequences milah, even though intention was very clear to protect his own people. But Yiddish Tril Maharaj did not object to Krishna and what has the view toward, and still, I saw the hell?
Bodha Talks: So, that is a Sharamagati. Sharamagati does not guarantee
Bodha Talks: absorbing your action, but even if the consequences come, accepting that as a Prasam. That is what the Pandavas are, that is what Pandava's life is, and that is what life exactly is.
Bodha Talks: You know, thank you, Marx.
Bodha Talks: I guess it's so increasing.
Bodha Talks: I think waited over 10 minutes left, so… It's really fun.
Bodha Talks: Any questions or comments? Any questions on this?
Bodha Talks: January.
Bodha Talks: Probably later you'll be addressing, you want to tell people who haven't… some of us who haven't probably read the story, you want to tell people what properties
Bodha Talks: Yeah, we'll take one… we'll do one session on the property also, yeah. Where he wanted… where she wanted those files. Yes, yes, yes. Be careful what we wish for.
Bodha Talks: I have you, Jen.
Bodha Talks: Nope.
Bodha Talks: Thank you.